Jose Oliver Benitez

<u>Portfolio</u> joliver017.github.io/Portfolio <u>LinkedIn</u> linkedin.com/in/jose-oliver-benitez

(512) 657-4490 | jose.oliver.benitez@gmail.com

Automation/Implementation Engineer

Engineer with a focus on migrating data and proven success implementing automated workflows. Writes code to make APIs talk to each other and perform required transformations and calculations. Graduate of Rice University and the UT Austin Coding Boot Camp. Works with JSON data and Ruby. Skills in HTML, CSS, Javascript, and databases. Recognized as adept technical leader with expertise understanding business requirements, identifying customer pain points, and implementing solutions that provide business value.

EXPERIENCE

Automation Engineer - Cloudsnap

2019 - present

- **Code functions** using Ruby to parse, generate, calculate and format JSON data tailored to client's needs.
- **Analyze database** diagrams/documentation and gain knowledge in API protocols and table relationships to ensure successful solutions installation, integration, and deployment.
- **Build workflows** for client's data integration needs between different ERP's (SAP Concur, NetSuite, Business Central, WorkDay, ADP, etc.)
- *Troubleshoot resolve platform and failing workflow issues.
- **Technical consultant** for enterprise customers ensuring technical integrity and high quality project delivery.
- **Proactively identify and capture** new opportunities leveraging engineering background to provide high levels of technical expertise.

Investigations Specialist - Accenture via BC Forward 2018 - 2019

- **Conduct deep** level investigations for malicious activity within client's social media platform.
- **Lead training** sessions for new team members.
- **'Identify and capture** new patterns of malicious behavior used to circumvent the platform's policy.
- **Generate and relay** feedback for improving team tools and productivity.
- **Serve as reliable** source of information to coworkers concerning policy and procedure.

DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

Languages/Front-End Back End/Databases

Javascript Ruby, Node.js

JSON, HTML5 MySQL
CSS (BootStrap, UI-Kit) MongoDB

GENERAL SKILLS

Spanish (Fluent) Teamwork

Typing Fast-learner

Editing Flexible

EDUCATION

University of Texas, Austin, TX

Coding Boot Camp 2018 - 2019

Rice University, Houston, TX

BA in Psychology 2011 - 2015

GPA: 3.79

Undergraduate coursework such as: Computer Applications in Psychology, Statistics, Research Methods, Social & Cognitive Psych.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

SME for NetSuite, Microsoft Business Central, WorkDay, ADP, and Google BigQuery.

Champion and work closely with enterprise customers to implement automated integrations.

Pivotal role in closing crucial deals driving thousands in MRR by providing integration and technical expertise.

Highest performance rating on Implementations team.

Selected for special 8-person Investigations team responsible for in-depth analysis of platform ads.

Top 10% performer; achieved a 98% accuracy rating in reviewing ads and maintained excellent productivity.

President's Honor Roll 2011-2012 and Fall 2013.